Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco. My
name is Catherine and today
we have an elementary-level
lesson for you.
This one is especially for people
who are interested in babies.
That's right, maybe you
have a baby, you will have a
baby, maybe you're pregnant
and this is a great lesson for
that because we are
talking about a baby shower.
Okay, so before we get
started let's take a look at the
tabula preview and learn what exactly a
baby shower is. Very cabaret-y preview.
Okay, so a baby shower. You
would think that this is about
bathing the baby about
giving the baby a bath.
No, not a real shower. A baby
shower or a bridal shower. These are
parties. Okay, they're parties
and in this case a baby shower is
a party that you throw for a
woman that is pregnant, right?
That's right. So if my sister is going to
have a baby, I throw her a baby shower.
It's a party where all of
her friends give her gifts.
Okay. Yeah, it's a way to
celebrate having a baby.
Okay, so they give her gifts.
You'll play games as well as to
like maybe guess the name of
the baby or guess the
sex of the baby. Exactly.
Stuff like that. Okay, so
it's a very common thing.
I think it's mostly for
a women. I don't really
I don't really know if men
have baby showers as well.
I don't think so. I
don't think so either,
but it's a very popular
tradition in the United
States and many
other parts of the world.
So we're going to talk about that. Let's
listen to the dialogue for the first time.
Thank you for organizing
this great baby shower for me.
I've always been to baby showers,
but never actually had one held for me.
Let's get started. Okay, let's
start opening some presents.
Oh, look. What a great
little bib for the baby.
This will definitely
come in handy. Oh, wow.
You also got me a stroller.
That's so great. Thank you.
This next one is from Betty.
Oh, hi, chair and a car seat.
Wow, Betty. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate it. One more from Carla.
A playpen and
crib. Thanks, Carla.
This is just what I needed.
Okay, that's all of them.
No more gifts. Now,
who wants to guess when
the baby is due? I think
my water just broke.
Get me to a hospital. All
right, so very interesting.
All the gifts that
they got and definitely
very useful because this
is a very common items
that you get for babies,
right? That's right.
All of this stuff is really,
really valuable because
if you have a baby or
if your brother or sister
has a baby, you'll notice that
these are very common items.
So let's go through
a couple of them
in today's language
takeaway. Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first word
that we're going to take a
look at the most common
one and useful one for
a baby is a bib. Bib.
So babies are messy.
When they eat food, they
get their food on their clothes.
So to protect the
clothes, babies wear bibs.
This is a piece of cloth
or fabric around their neck.
Okay, a bib. And also, sometimes you
want to go out with your baby to the mall.
You're walking and you
don't want to carry him in your
arms all the time. So
you need a stroller.
Okay, so basically a
stroller is a chair on wheels
for a baby. Babies are
heavy and as they get
older, they get heavier.
And so this is a way to
push the baby around,
not carry the baby. Right.
And maybe the baby
falls asleep so they can
fall asleep in the
stroller. Exactly. Okay.
And while talking about
chairs, we're going to take a look
at two different
types of chairs.
First one is a high chair. Okay,
high chair, think about the word high.
That means tall in this case.
A high chair is a chair
for babies at the table.
So if you put a baby on a regular
chair, they can't eat with adults.
They're too small. So
we give them a high
chairs so that they
can sit a little bit higher
and they can be at
the table with adults.
Exactly. So they're very common.
For example, you go to a
restaurant, they will have a little
high chairs if you have
a baby or a small child.
So if you're at a
restaurant, you have a baby,
you ask for a high chair. You say, do you
have a high chair, please? Yeah. Perfect.
And well, if you're going to the
restaurant or you go anywhere
in your car, you need
to have the baby be safe
and obviously they
can't fit on a normal, you
know, seat right there.
No, with the seat belt.
No, I don't think so. So that's
why you get them a car seat.
Okay. A car seat is a
special chair that goes
on the seat of the car. And
usually it's very, very safe.
It's protecting. It's
made to protect the baby.
Right. So if you are
ever in a car accident,
the car seat will help
protect the small baby.
Right. And car seats are
supposed to go in the
back of the car, not
the front. Yes, always.
Very good. And now moving
on to our last two words.
If you're at home, you
sometimes want to have
the baby play and you
get them a play pen.
So basically, this is a
way for parents to leave
the baby playing, but not
look at the baby the whole time.
Right. A play pen is
like a cage for a baby,
but it's soft and it's
cute and it's pretty.
And so it's basically
like an open area that's
protected on the sides
and the baby can go inside,
but the baby can't leave.
Right. It's like a cage
basically and has little
toys and that's the way
you just keep them in
there. Exactly. All right.
And now when you want
to put the baby to sleep,
it can't obviously sleep
in a big bed because it
might roll over in my
fall off. There's a lot of
things that can go wrong.
So you get them a crib.
Right. So crib is
a bed for babies.
This is usually high off the
ground. And it's usually quite
small and the baby
can't climb out of it. Right.
Yeah. So it's a very safe
bed. So the baby can't
fall out, can't climb
out. Exactly. Very good.
So very interesting,
very useful things for you.
If you're having a baby planning on getting
these things. So why don't we go back,
listen to the dialogue again and
we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
Thank you for organizing
this great baby shower for me.
I've always been to baby showers,
but never actually had one held for me.
Let's get started. Okay. Let's
start opening some presents.
Oh, look. What a great little bib for the
baby. This will definitely come in handy.
Oh, wow. You also got me a stroller.
That's so great. Thank you.
This next one is from Betty.
Oh, hi, chair and a car seat.
Wow, Betty. Thank you so much.
I really appreciate it. One more
from Carla. A playpen and crib.
Thanks, Carla. This
is just what I needed.
Okay. That's all of
them. No more gifts.
Now, who wants to guess
when the baby is due?
Um, I think my water just broke.
Get me to a hospital.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a
look at two key phrases. Fluency Builder.
Okay. So at the beginning
of the dialogue, the
woman recedes a bit
for the baby and she says,
oh, this will definitely come
in handy to come in handy.
Right. So when something comes in
handy, it means it will be useful. Okay.
So something that's handy is useful
to come in handy means to be useful.
It will be useful in the future.
So for example, you should
take a flashlight with you in the
car just in case because
it could come in handy.
That's right. Or if I know
that Marco is traveling
to India, I can give
him a map of India.
I say Marco, this map might
come in handy. Exactly. Very good.
So to come in handy or
in something that is handy,
something that's useful.
And towards the end
of very popular phrase,
you probably heard an
every movie that has like maybe
a pregnant women in there.
Oh, yes. My water just broke. My
water broke. Okay. So the woman says,
ah, my water broke.
Take me to the hospital.
Right. Okay. So this means
I'm having my baby right now.
So why do they what do they say that the
water broke? Because actually water kind of
breaks, right? I think
there's a protective.
Yeah, there's a. Basically,
there's a sack of water
protecting the baby.
It's not just water.
It's all sorts of like, fluid
fight fluids. And basically,
when that breaks, it
comes out and you know
that you're going to
have the baby because that
means the baby has to
come out now because that
protective fluid is gone.
Maybe the baby just kind of
kicks that water out and just
like, I'm ready to come out.
I have no idea
how many. All right.
So very interesting stuff. Why don't we
listen to the dialogue for the last time.
Thank you for organizing
this great baby shower for me.
I've always been to baby showers,
but never actually had one held for me.
Let's get started. Okay. Let's
start opening some presents.
Oh, look. What a great little bib for the
baby. This will definitely come in handy.
Oh, wow. You also got me a stroller.
That's so great. Thank you.
This next one is from Betty.
Oh, hi, chair and a car seat.
Wow, Betty. Thank you so much.
I really appreciate it. One more
from Carla. A play pen and crib.
Thanks, Carla. This
is just what I needed.
Okay. That's all of
them. No more gifts.
Now, who wants to guess
when the baby is due?
Um, I think my water just broke.
Get me to a hospital.
All right. So talking about baby things and
baby showers. Um, it's a very interesting
tradition. I understand
that in other countries,
they don't really celebrate
baby showers like this.
Really? Yeah. Or
that if they do, they
do it in different ways.
Um, I know for example,
that sometimes in Latin American countries,
they usually do it after the baby's born.
Oh, so like a congratulations
shower. Exactly.
And then obviously you
know if the baby was a boy
or girls, then you get them
like pink things or blue things.
So it's a little bit more.
That's what's really
funny about these.
People often want to have,
uh, the surprise of not knowing
if the baby will
be a boy or a girl.
So when they have the baby
shower, they say, Oh, I don't
know what the gender is. Right. And so you
end up buying all of these yellow things.
His yellow is neutral. It's
good for boys and girls. Yeah.
I don't know how many
yellow gifts I've got.
I think, uh, it's a very
interesting thing because
in, for example, I know
that in China, I think
you can't ask the doctor
for the gender of the
baby on before it's born,
right? Uh, I think that's
a way to, I'm not sure
if it's a rule or not, but
it sounds right. I mean, it's, it's
a way to protect female babies.
I think it would be always
great to just have it be a surprise.
You never know. Yeah.
Just like, oh, you know,
whatever comes out. Can
you imagine not knowing it
when you have twins
or that would be great for
me. I think if I had
like a boy and a girl,
bam, all at once, all
at once, never have
to worry about it exactly. And then you
have best both worlds, right? You're done.
All right. So a very
interesting topic. Let us know.
If you have baby showers
in your country or how do
you celebrate a baby's birth or
before it's born, what do you do?
Very good question. Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you
there. All right. Bye. Bye.